[
    {
      "question": "In C, parameters are always?",
      "options": [
        "A. Passed by value",
        "B. Passed by reference",
        "C. Non-pointer variables are passed by value and pointers are passed by reference",
        "D. Passed by value result"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Passed by value"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following sorting algorithms can be used to sort a random linked list with minimum time complexity?",
      "options": [
        "A. Insertion Sort",
        "B. Quick Sort",
        "C. Heap Sort",
        "D. Merge Sort"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Merge Sort"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the limitation of the array?",
      "options": [
          "A. Elements can be accessed from anywhere.", 
          "B. The size of the array is fixed.", 
          "C. Indexing is started from Zero.", 
          "D. Memory waste if an array's elements are smaller than the size allotted to them"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Memory waste if an array's elements are smaller than the size allotted to them"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following cannot generate the full binary tree?",
      "options": [
          "A. Inorder and Preorder", 
          "B. Inorder and Postorder", 
          "C. Preorder and Postorder", 
          "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "D. None of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one among the following radiations carries maximum energy?",
      "options": [
        "A. Ultraviolet rays",
        "B. Gamma rays",
        "C. X- rays",
        "D. Infra-red rays"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Gamma rays"
    },
    {
      "question": "The head quarters of world trade organization is in?",
      "options": [
        "A. Montreal",
        "B. Seattle",
        "C. Geneva",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "C. Geneva"
    },
    {
      "question": "The language spoken by the people by Pakistan is ?",
      "options": ["A. Hindi", "B. Nepali", "C. English", "D. Sindhi"],
      "answer": "D. Sindhi"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following requires a device driver?",
      "options": [
        "A. Register",
        "B. Cache",
        "C. Main memory",
        "D. Disk"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Disk"
    },
    {
      "question": "'LIBRA' an alternative of existing cryptocurrency like bitcoin is being developed by?",
      "options": [
        "A. Facebook",
        "B. Google",
        "C. Microsoft",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Facebook"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the followings is/are automatically added to every class, if we do not write our own?",
      "options": [
        "A. Copy Constructor",
        "B. Assignment Operator",
        "C. A constructor without any parameter",
        "D.  All the above"
      ],
      "answer": "D.  All the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Headquater of International Olympic Committee is situated at?",
      "options": ["A. Athens", "B. Lausanne", "C. Dubai", "D. None of the above"],
      "answer": "B. Lausanne"
    },
    {
      "question": "When the inheritance is private, the private methods in base class are __________ in the derived class (in C++)?",
      "options": [
        "A. inaccessible",
        "B. accessible",
        "C. protected",
        "D. public"
      ],
      "answer": "A. inaccessible"
    },
    {
      "question": "The metal whose salts are sensitive to light is?",
      "options": ["A. Silver", "B. Zinc", "C. Copper", "D. Gold"],
      "answer": "A. Silver"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
      "options": ["A. Aristotle", "B. Euclid", "C. Pythagoras", "D. Kepler"],
      "answer": "B. Euclid"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is called when a function is defined inside a class?",
      "options": [
        "A. Module",
        "B. Class",
        "C. Another Function",
        "D. Method"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Method"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
      "options": [
        "A. Id returns the identity of the object",
        "B. Every object doesn’t have a unique id",
        "C. All of the mentioned",
        "D. None of the mentioned"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Every object doesn’t have a unique id"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
      "options": ["A. Aristotle", "B. Euclid", "C. Pythagoras", "D. Kepler"],
      "answer": "B. Euclid"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following operator functions cannot be global, i.e., must be a member function?",
      "options": [
          "A. new", 
          "B. delete", 
          "C. Converstion Operator", 
          "D. All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "C. Converstion Operator"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the current chief of the world bank group?",
      "options": [
        "A. Donald Tusk",
        "B. David Malpass",
        "C. Christine Lagarde",
        "D. Jim Yong Kim"
      ],
      "answer": "B. David Malpass"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Second World War started?",
      "options": [
        "A. September 1, 1939",
        "B. September 1, 1940",
        "C. September 1, 1945",
        "D. September 1, 1942"
      ],
      "answer": "A. September 1, 1939"
    },
    {
      "question": "Each year World Red Cross and Red Crescent Day is celebrated on?",
      "options": ["A. May 8", "B. May 18", "C. June 8", "D. June 19"],
      "answer": "A. May 8"
    },
    {
      "question": "The brain fever which affects young children is?",
      "options": ["A. Malaria", "B. Typhoid", "C. Encephalitis", "D. Pneumonia"],
      "answer": "C. Encephalitis"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the first search engine of the internet?",
      "options": ["A. Yahoo", "B. Wais", "C. Archie", "D. Mozilla"],
      "answer": "C. Archie"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a Database Management System(DBMS) the content and the location of data is identified by ?",
      "options": [
        "A. Subdata",
        "B. Sequence Data",
        "C. Beta Data",
        "D. Meta Data"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Meta Data"
    },
    {
      "question": "'.MOV' extensions refer to which kind of file?",
      "options": [
        "A. Image file",
        "B. Movie File",
        "C. Audio File",
        "D. ZIP File"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Movie File"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who wrote the famous poem 'The Charge of the Light Brigade'?",
      "options": [
        "A. Lord Alfred Tennyson",
        "B. Christopher Marlowe",
        "C. Johannes Gutenberg",
        "D. Rene Descartes"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Lord Alfred Tennyson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who founded Indian National Army(INA)?",
      "options": [
        "A. Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "B. Mohan Singh",
        "C. Rash Behari Bose",
        "D. Jatridranath Mukherjee"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Mohan Singh"
    },
    {
      "question": "The control of which state was handed over to british after marriage of King Charles 2 with portuguese princess in 1661?",
      "options": ["A. Cochin", "B. Bombay", "C. Surat", "D. Madras"],
      "answer": "B. Bombay"
    },
    {
      "question": " Country that has the highest in Barley Production ?",
      "options": ["A. China", "B. India", "C. Russia", "D. France"],
      "answer": "C. Russia"
    },
    {
      "question": "The World Largest desert is ?",
      "options": ["A. Thar", "B. Kalahari", "C. Sahara", "D. Sonoran"],
      "answer": "C. Sahara"
    },
    {
      "question": "Guru Gopi Krishna is popular for which form of Indian dance?",
      "options": ["A. Bharatanatyam", "B. Kuchipudi", "C. Kathak", "D. Manipuri"],
      "answer": "B. Kuchipudi"
    },
    {
      "question": "J.B. Dunlop is popular for which of the following inventions?",
      "options": [
        "A. Model airplanes",
        "B. Pneumatic rubber tire",
        "C. Rubber boot",
        "D. Automobile wheel rim"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Pneumatic rubber tire"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who built this project ?",
      "options": ["Aman", "Nutan", "Shyam", "Ram"],
      "answer": "Aman"
    }
  ]
  